Francis Gurr

Sheffield, UK

francis.gurr@gmail.com

francisgurr.com

francis-gurr
Francis-Gurr

Summary

I have two years of experience as a software engineer, with a primary focus on front-end development, although my interest also extends to full-stack.

I am passionate about continuous learning and enjoy working in challenging environments that facilitate personal and professional growth.

Working on personal programming projects is not only a hobby for me, but also an opportunity to expand my skillset and experiment with new technologies. While I have some examples of my work on my website and GitHub, many of my projects are small experiments that I enjoy tinkering with on my home server.

When I am not at the computer, you can find me rock climbing, mountain unicycling and occasionally juggling.

Education

Master of Engineering Electronic Engineering

Durham University 2015 - 2020

Skills

Lots of experience with:

Javascript Vue.js HTML CSS

Jest Cypress Python Git

Some experience with:

Go Java Ruby C C++ GCP

Languages:

English German

Experience

Software Engineer *Pendo* **Associate Software Engineer**

Aug 2022 - Present Jun 2021 - Jul 2022

- Developed and implemented a roadmapping tool from scratch
- Acquired expertise in various technologies, including JavaScript, Vue.js, and testing using Jest and Cypress
- Assumed the role of team tech lead, overseeing project development and ensuring successful outcomes while the regular tech lead was on paternity leave earlier this year
- Mentored associate developers and onboarded new team members
- Delivered presentations on various topics, showcasing in-depth knowledge of the subject matter and engaging audiences effectively
- Recipient of the most Pank awards in the category "Win Together" in Q1,
 FY24 (Pank awards are Pendo's peer recognition program)
- Assisted in organising an internal product and engineering conference
- Participated in customer support calls
- Contributed to building the office culture by starting a weekly climbing club

Masters Project - 1st Class (80%) Durham University 2020

- Utilized machine learning to detect and provide real-time vehicle speed from roadside camera footage
- Developed Python software to calibrate the camera using road markings and used C++ to calculate vehicle speeds
- The results were published in a paper in the International Journal of Intelligent Transportation Systems Research 20 (2022) under the title "Camera-Based System for the Automatic Detection of Vehicle Axle Count and Speed Using Convolutional Neural Networks", DOI: 10.1007/s13177-022-00325-1
- The project was sponsored by Q-Free and aimed to add a unique product to the market with a non-intrusive alternative to current ITS and infomobility systems

See more on my website 🗹

R&D Internship *Q-Free*

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

- Designed an innovative prototype for a non-intrusive roadside detection system to count and classify vehicles during my third-year design project
- Awarded a summer internship by Q-Free to develop a working prototype of my design
- Developed software in C to process LiDAR and radar sensor data and used
 Python to generate real-time 2D side profiles of each vehicle

See more on my website 🗹

Research Internship Durham University **Jun 2018 - Feb 2019**

- Summer internship with the Department of Maths and Computer Science
- Developed a classification algorithm in Python to recursively generate unique radius two local configurations of quartic graphs
- The results formed the basis of the main theorem in an academic research paper "Quartic Graphs that are Bakry-Émery Curvature Sharp", published in Discrete Mathematics 343 (3), DOI: 10.1016/j.disc.2019.111767 ☑

See more on my website 🗹